-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 潇妹纸 袋鼠 有个饭团 凤梨酥 汐颜viola
校对: 影子
这是战争前的地球
Earth, before the war.
这是我出生前的纽约
New York, before I was born.
这个地方我只从照片上看到过
A place I've only seen pictures of.
我认识你...
I know you...
可我们从未见过
but we've never met.
我和你心心相映...
I'm with you...
却连你的名字都不知道
but I don't know your name.
我一定是在做梦 可又如此真实
I know I'm dreaming. But it feels like more than that.
就好像是在回忆过往
It feels like a memory.
怎么会这样?
How can that be?
2077年3月14日
March 14th, 2077.
自强制消除记忆以来 已经过去了5年
Five years since the mandatory memory wipe.
而我仍受这些梦境的困扰
And I'm still haunted by these dreams.
维多利亚和我被安排一起任务
Victoria and I were assigned together.
两周后 这里的任务即将完成 我们会与其他人会合
In two weeks, our mission here will be finished, and we'll join the others.
可她不明白我的疑问
But the questions I ask, she doesn't.
也不明白我在思考的问题
The things I wonder about, she won't.
外星掠夺者毁坏月球已是半个世纪以前的事情
It's been half a century since the scavengers destroyed our moon.
被迫离开自己即将灭亡星球的他们 来侵略我们的家园
Forced to leave their own dying planet, they came to take ours.
月球毁灭之后 地球陷入混乱
Without the moon, the Earth was thrown into chaos.
地震于数小时内倾覆了诸多城市
Earthquakes toppled cities within hours.
海啸帮地震做了扫尾工作
Tsunamis wiped out what remained.
接着就是入侵开始
Then came the invasion.
我们做了该做的事
We did what we had to do.
我们发射了核弹
We used the nukes.
我们赢得了战争 却输掉了地球
We won the war, but lost the planet.
使之饱受污染荼毒 大部分地区已不适宜居住
Left it contaminated. Most of it uninhabitable.
残存的人类不得不逃离地球
What remained of humanity had to leave the Earth.
我们建成了指挥中心泰特
We built the Tet, our mission control.
作为移民土星最大卫星泰坦星之前的
A temporary space station before the migration to Titan,
临时空间站
Saturn's largest moon.
所有人都已去了泰坦星
Everyone's there now.
几乎所有人
Well, almost everyone.
维卡和我在任务结束之前 都要恪守本职
Until our tour is complete, Vika and I do our job.
我们的任务是保护水电装置
We protect the hydro rigs,
这一装置能将地球上的海洋水体
which convert Earth's sea water
转化成供新殖民地使用的聚变能
into fusion energy for the new colony.
人类的生存全赖于此
The survival of humanity depends on it.
谢谢你的咖啡
Thank you for the coffee.
外星掠夺者的残余部队不断进行破坏
Remnants of the scavenger army continue to disrupt the operation.
它们夜袭我们的无人机
They attack our drones at night,
白天则要置我于死地
and try to kill me during the day.
他们仍在战斗 可我不明就里
There's still fight in them, but I don't know why.
任务指挥中心说我们做得很好
Mission says we have done well.
说我们是最佳组合
That we are an effective team.
维卡是我的导航官
Vika's my communications officer.
她关注着我的一举一动
She keeps an eye on me.
我负责无人机维护
I handle drone maintenance.
而无人机则保护着一切
The drones watch everything.
维卡迫不及待要离开 我还在徘徊
Vika can't wait to go. Me, I'm not so sure.
虽然发生了这么多事
I can't shake the feeling that Earth,
我仍然无法甩掉那种感觉...
in spite of all that's happened...
觉得地球仍然是我的家园
Earth is still my home.
片名: 遗落战境
杰克・哈珀 49号技术员
Jack Harper, Tech-49.
49号技术员 已确认
早上好 鲍伯
Morning, Bob.
指挥塔 检查通讯
Tower, comm check.
49号无人机维护技术员 水电装置支持中心
Drone Maintenance Technician 49, hydro rig support.
气泡飞行器所有系统正常
All Bubbleship systems are green.
我准备好出发了
I'm good to go.
收到 49号技术员 可以起飞 注意安全
Copy, Tech-49, you're cleared. Be careful out there.
- 时刻注意着呢  - 你才没注意
- Always am.  - No, you're not.
好吧 你说得对 我努力注意好了
Yeah, you're right. I gotta work on that.
离线
好了 泰特将在30秒内上线
All right, Tet's coming online in 30 seconds.
马上传输水电装置坐标 请观察装置运作情况
Relaying hydro rig coordinates now. Confirm visual.
看到了 水电装置正在吸纳海水
I got 'em. Hydro rigs are sucking seawater.
鲍伯 你看到了吗?
You got 'em, Bob?
185号无人机正常
Drone 185 looks good.
杰克 有两架无人机坏了
Jack, we've got two drones down.
混蛋
Shit.
原地待命 指挥中心快上线了
Stand by, Mission coming online.
已连接泰特
And we have Tet contact.
早上好 老大
Morning, boss.
离线
在线
第49号指挥塔 这里是指挥中心
Tower 49, this is Mission Control.
在这个阳光明媚的早上 你们进展如何?
How y'all doing this lovely morning?
萨利 如天堂一般 正在上传数据
Another day in paradise, Sally. Uploading data now.
49号任务日志 第1642天 水电装置支持中心
49 mission log. Day 1642, hydro rig support.
- 有两个...  - 有两个无人机失去联系
- I have two...  - You have two drones offline.
边界遭到入侵
Perimeter's compromised.
收到 正在将消息转达技术员 稍等
Copy that, relaying to Tech. Stand by.
杰克 166号无人机坠落在在37区
Jack, 166 is down in Grid 37.
正在连接指挥塔
Linking to beacon now.
你先去那儿
You'll go there first.
收到 这就出发
Got it. On my way.
指挥中心 49号技术员正在赶往37区
Mission, Tech-49 is en route to Grid 37 now.
你能让109号无人机补上那个漏洞吗?
Can you plug that hole with Drone 109?
不能 109号仍在舱里等候配件
Negative, 109 is in the dock. Still waiting for parts.
杰克最好能找到那些无人机 让它们再次运转起来
Jack better find those drones and get 'em flying.
这些水电装置不能整夜暴露在外
Those rigs can't be exposed overnight.
明白
Copy that.
指挥塔 他最近没修好166号无人机吗?
Tower, didn't he fix 166 recently?
杰克最近把所有无人机都修好了
Jack has fixed all the drones recently.
另外 如果要求的配件到手
And, if we had the parts that we've been asking for,
现在就不至于这么狼狈了
we wouldn't be running a skeleton crew down here.
明白 我们正在想方设法
Understood. We're doing the best we can.
你们是最佳组合吗?
Are you an effective team?
我们是最佳组合
We are an effective team.
你们今天的任务就是修复166号无人机
Your directive today is to rehabilitate 166
找到172号无人机
and find 172.
日落前让它们恢复飞行
Get 'em flying by sundown,
等你们到了泰特 我就请你们俩喝酒
and I'll buy you two a round of drinks when you get up to the Tet.
萨利 你准备好请客吧
You had better be ready, Sally.
已经两周了 我们一直在注意动向
Two weeks now, we're keeping track.
好吧
Okay.
别这样 鲍伯 老兄 配合一点
Come on, Bob. Work with me, here, buddy.
49号技术员?
Tech-49?
杰克?
Jack?
指挥塔 收到
Copy, Tower.
发生什么事了? 我刚才没看到你的行踪
What happened? I lost you for a second.
是吗?
Really?
正在赶往事故地点
Coming up on location.
到了
There it is.
现场有多只外星掠夺者的残骸
I've got multiple scav kills.
166号无人机拼死顽抗
Drone 166 put up a hell of a fight.
有动静吗?
Got any movement?
未发现外星掠夺者
No sign of scavenger activity.
杰克 指挥中心角度较低 我这儿视野有限
But I've got limited visibility, here, Jack, due to low angle of Mission.
明白 我这就着陆
Copy that. I'm coming in hot.
开始维修 帮我警戒周围
Starting repairs. Watch my back.
一如既往
I always do.
2017年世界冠军杯赛
知道吗 我读过有关这场比赛的文章
You know, I read about this game.
比赛当时就在这里进行
It was played right here.
是最后一届超级碗
The last Super Bowl.
不会是经典赛事吧
Please don't tell me it was a classic.
是经典赛事
A classic game.
落后四分
Down by four.
球的位置
The ball
在50码线上
was on the 50-yard line.
时间只剩几秒钟
Seconds left on the clock.
球被紧紧盯防
The ball is snapped,
四分卫失球
and the QB fumbles.
悲剧
Disaster.
比赛似乎已成定局
Looks like the game is over.
中央核心完全偏转
I'm reading the whole central core off-alignment.
你那儿没有称手的工具
You don't have the necessary tools down there.
光替换新的燃料电池是修不好的
And a new fuel cell is not going to fix that.
但四分卫跑了回来 捡起他失掉的球
But this QB runs back, and picks up his own fumble.
等等 你刚才干嘛了?
Hold on, what did you just do?
对方中后卫球员排成人墙逼近
There's a wall of linebackers closing in on him.
于是他来了个长传 连接球手是谁都不知道
So, he throws a long ball with no idea who is at the other end.
圣母玛利亚啊
A Hail Mary.
8万观众都站了起来
Eighty-thousand people on their feet,
看着这个球划过天空
watching this ball sail through the air.
位于前场的是一个三流的菜鸟外接员
Downfield is a rookie wide receiver, third string.
他从人墙后奋勇而出
He just leaps out of the pack.
触地得分!
Touchdown!
警报
有敌人! 西面有敌人!
Contact! West contact!
杰克?
Jack?
没事 维卡
It's okay, Vika.
不过是条狗
It's just a dog.
嘿
Hey.
好了 走吧 离开这儿
Now, go on. You gotta get out of here.
快走啊!
Go on, get!
离开这儿! 快跑!
Get out of here! Go!
49号技术员 杰克・哈珀
Tech-49, Jack Harper.
安全
连句谢谢也不说
You're welcome.
166号恢复运转
166 is back online.
今天有两架无人机被干掉 一个月内就有十个燃料电池被偷
Two drones shot down today. Ten fuel cells stolen in just over a month.
那些外星掠夺者越来越明目张胆了
These scavs are getting bolder.
不过水电装置正在提取水源
Well, the hydro rigs are taking all the water.
一旦我们离开 他们就只有辐射和尘埃了
Once we're gone, they'll have nothing but dust and radiation.
这太扯了
This is bullshit.
我们明明赢了战争
We won the war.
现在却不得不离开
Now we have to leave.
就剩两周了 杰克
Two more weeks, Jack.
之后我们就能去泰坦星了
Then we'll be on our way to Titan.
没错
Yep.
那个无人机肯定在这里
That drone is out there somewhere.
我们只要找到就行
We just have to find it.
要是没有指挥塔指引的话 就像大海捞针
Without a beacon, that's like finding a needle in a haystack.
那我们就动身去找吧
So we go to our ground game.
指挥塔 我找到172号了
Tower, I've located 172
在深坑下面
down a sinkhole.
看不见 但能听到声音
No visual, but I can hear it.
泰特的角度不好 我这里看不到你
Tet's so far off angle, I can barely see you.
情况怎样?
How's it look?
还行 地面上没有外星掠夺者活动的痕迹
It's good, it's good. There's no sign of scav activity on top.
泰特15分钟后离线
Tet's offline in 15 minutes.
之后就靠你自己了
After that, you're on your own.
指挥中心 这里是第49号指挥塔
Mission, this is Tower 49.
杰克已经定位172号无人机 现在正前去维修
Jack has located Drone 172. Engaged in recovery now.
请求尽快提供支援
Requesting backup to his location ASAP.
我看到172号无人机了
I've got a visual on Drone 172.
杰克?
Jack?
这是什么?
What the hell?
该死
Shit.
哈!
Ha!
杰克!
Jack!
49号技术员 杰克・哈珀
Tech-49, Jack Harper.
杰克・哈珀 49号技术员!
Jack Harper, Tech-49!
嘿!
Hey!
不
Oh, no.
该死 我的车呢!
Come on. Not my goddamn bike!
"有什么比与厄运抗争而死 更死得其所"
"How can a man die better. Than facing fearful odds."
"为了寻找先祖的遗迹 以及其信仰的殿堂"
"For the ashes of his fathers. And the temples of his Gods."
杰克?
Jack?
好 我马上过去
Yep, I'll be right there.
古罗马之歌
109号情况怎样?
How does 109 look?
能飞吗?
Can it fly?
飞不了
Barely.
而且没有装甲 她就是个瓮中之鳖
And without armor, she's a sitting duck.
我明早跟萨利说装甲配件的事
Well, I'll talk to Sally about that shielding in the morning.
好的
Okay.
再说一遍
Again.
怎么了 杰克・哈珀?
What, Jack Harper?
你从哪弄到的?
Where did you get this?
就长在...
It was growing in...
好了 杰克 你很清楚规定
Come on, Jack, you know the regulations.
你知道你觉得我很固执
I know you think I'm a stickler
但你并不知道这里面
but you have no idea what kind of toxins
会有什么样的毒素
could be in something like that.
只是朵花 维卡
It's a flower, Vika.
没错 但那不是重点
Yeah, that's not the point.
我们马上就熬到头了
It's that we are so close to the end,
我可不允许你干傻事毁了它
and the last thing that we need is you putting it all at risk.
好吧
Okay.
每天你都要下去
Every day, you have to go down there
检查丢了些什么
and see what was lost.
但我们已经完成任务了 杰克
But we've done our job, Jack.
是时候离开了
It's time to go.
我觉得他们今天并没有打算杀我
I don't think they were trying to kill me today.
那些外星掠夺者
The scavs.
他们只是想要抓住我
They were trying to catch me.
他们抓不了你
Well, they can't have you.
过来
Come on.
我们走之前 你应该跟我一起下去几次
You should come with me sometime, before we leave.
我发现了个好地方 想带你看看
There's a place I found I'd like to show you.
我有东西给你看
I'll show you something.
嘿 嘿!
Hey, hey!
天啊
Oh, my God.
这次是水电装置中心发生六级垮塌
It was a six-stage meltdown from inside the hydro rig's core.
装置已经彻底报废了
It's offline permanently.
第49号指挥塔 你让整个任务都面临危险
Tower 49, you have put the whole operation at risk.
我要知道到底发生了什么事
I need to know exactly what happened.
杰克认为是外星掠夺者将偷走的一个燃料电池做成武器
Jack believes the scavs weaponized one of the stolen fuel cells
然后放进了装置
and got it into the suction.
指挥塔 等一下
Tower, hold.
指挥塔 我收到了从37区里发出的信号 你看到了吗?
Tower, I've got a rogue signal in Grid 37. Are you seeing this?
是的
Yes.
应该是外星掠夺者
It's gotta be scav.
不是我们的信号
It's not one of ours.
杰克 信号被定向至星外的
Jack, the signal is being directed off-planet.
马上赶到
On my way.
指挥塔 我们的记录显示你还丢失了九个的燃料电池
Tower, our logs show you are missing an additional nine fuel cells.
你能确认吗?
Can you confirm?
不对 指挥中心 是10个
Negative, Mission, that number is 10.
172号无人机昨晚不见了
Drone 172 was lost last night.
只要我们有了装甲配件 109号就能投入战斗
109 is combat-ready as soon as we get that shielding.
我们能用无人机修好陆地上剩下的水电装置
We can cover the remaining rigs with drones in the field.
我已经运行数据了
I've run the numbers.
数据由我们来运行 指挥塔
We'll do the numbers up here, Tower.
我正在给无人机发布防御任务
I'm tasking the drones to defensive positions.
明白
Copy.
我们的工作是运行那些水电装置 你们的任务就是保护它们
Our job is to run those rigs. Your directive is to protect them.
我们不能再失去其它装置了 你明白吗?
We cannot afford to lose another. Do you copy?
明白
Copy.
你和J杰克还是最佳组合吗?
Are you and Jack an effective team?
我们当然是
Damn right we are.
杰克?
Jack?
你就在正上方 看到什么了吗?
You're right on top of it. Do you have a visual?
杰克?
Jack?
是 我看到了
Yeah, I got it.
他们有一个类似转发器的东西
They have some kind of a repeater.
那些外星掠夺者用这座建筑做天线
The scavs are using the building as an antenna.
你能破解吗?
Can you decrypt?
这是一组坐标
It's a set of coordinates.
17区
Grid 17.
是个该死的导航信号
It's a goddamn homing beacon.
17区
Grid 17.
那里有些什么?
What the hell is out there?
没有 什么都没有
Nothing. It's the middle of nowhere.
怎么了?
What is going on?
为什么这些外星掠夺者把信号发到外星 杰克?
Why would the scavs send a signal off-planet, Jack?
我来关闭它
I'm shutting it down.
49号技术员 检查你的路径 你前面就是边界了
Tech-49, check your course. You're headed right for the border.
辐射会在你意识到之前就把你烤熟的
That radiation will cook you from the inside before you know it.
没事 维卡 我看到了
It's okay, Vika. I see it.
我回家之前会在边界巡逻一遍
I'm gonna do a perimeter check before I head home.
可能通讯会断
I may go off-comm.
杰克 我们应该保持联系
Jack, we should keep in contact.
至少让我知道你在哪
Just let me know where you are.
明白吗?
Do you copy?
杰克 你明白吗?
Jack, do you copy?
就是这样 鲍伯
That's right, Bob.
你知道我们要去哪
You know where we're going.
你会想我吗?
Are you gonna miss me?
我会想念这个地方的
I'm gonna miss this place.
本来可以很美好的
It would have been great.
维卡? 维卡 你收到了吗?
Vika? Vika, did you get that?
杰克 你去哪了?
Jack, where have you been?
有不明飞行物坠落在17区
An object came down in 17.
那就是信号坐标
That's the beacon coordinates.
没错
Exactly.
我看到了 有点像容器
I saw it. Some sort of vessel.
杰克 指挥中心快离线了
Jack, Mission's almost offline.
我在路上了
I'm en route now.
指挥中心 我们发现不明飞行物降落在17区
Mission, we have an unidentified object impact in 17.
降落位置正是外星掠夺者发出的信号坐标
It came down at coordinates sent by a scav beacon.
我的技术员已经在路上
My tech's en route now.
指挥塔 我们马上就要离线
Tower, we're going offline soon,
但是无人机已经过去执行任务了
but drones are already mobile and executing.
让你的技术员撤退
Have your tech stand down.
杰克 指挥中心让你撤退 无人机会解决他们
Jack, Mission wants you to stand down. The drones will handle it.
否认 指挥塔
That's a negative, Tower.
没有泰特在线 我们更得看着这里
With Tet offline, we need our eyes on this.
我要知道这片区域是安全的
I want to know this site is secure.
萨利 我的技术员担心区域的安全问题
Sally, my tech's concerned about the security of the site.
指挥塔 你们今天失去的资源已经够多了
Tower, you have lost enough assets for today.
让你的技术员离开那里 明白吗?
Keep your tech out of there. Do you copy?
明白 指挥官 我...
Copy, Command, I'm...
杰克 指挥官命令你撤退 无人机会解决问题
Jack, Command wants you to stand down. The drones will handle this.
我已经到了
I'm on site.
杰克
Jack.
我看不到你 指挥中心离线了
I don't have eyes on you. Command's offline.
维卡 我觉得这是我们的同类
Vika, I think it's one of ours.
这东西很古老 看起来...
This thing is ancient. It looks...
像是战前的
pre-war.
这东西是那些外星掠夺者的杰克
The scavs brought this thing down, Jack.
没有掠夺者的踪迹
There's no sign of scavs.
技术员 我是你的导航官
Technician, this is your Control.
我命令你立即撤离回塔
I'm ordering you to pull out and return to the tower immediately.
准备降落
Touching down.
是人类
They're human.
指挥塔 发现幸存者
Tower, we have got survivors.
有四个... 不 五个幸存者
There are four... Check it, five survivors.
是人类
They are human.
住手!
Stand down!
维卡 无人机在向幸存者开火
Vika, the drones are firing on survivors.
杰克 指挥中心不在线 我没法控制
Jack, the Tet's offline. I don't have control.
住手!
Stand down!
杰克・哈珀 49号技术员
Jack Harper, Tech-49.
滚开 该死的东西!
Back off, you son of a bitch!
滚开!
Back off!
开门
Open the door.
维卡!
Vika!
拿急救箱来
Get the med kit.
拿急救箱来!
Get the med kit!
这必须上报指挥中心
This has to be reported.
把无人机屠杀我们自己飞船的船员
Be sure and report that the drones
也汇报上去
killed the crew from one of our own ships.
看是哪条规定让它们这么做的
See what Command makes of that.
是呼吸液 吐出来就好了
It's breathing fluid. Just let her get it out.
杰克
Jack.
来 你还脱水呢
Here. You're still dehydrated.
我们在哪?
Where are we?
我是维多利亚 他是杰克
I'm Victoria, this is Jack.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
我叫茱莉亚
I'm Julia.
茱莉亚...
Julia...
我对接下来要告诉你的事深表遗憾
I'm sorry for what I have to tell you,
你的飞船在降落中
but you were in a crash.
坠毁了
Your ship came down.
是杰克把你从废墟中救出来
Jack managed to pull you from the wreckage.
但其他船员都遇难了
But none of your crew survived.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
你是唯一的幸存者
You're the only one that made it.
节哀
I'm sorry.
你已经沉睡了很久
You've been in delta sleep for a long time.
有头晕的感觉是正常的
Some disorientation is normal.
多久?
How long?
60年
Sixty years.
至少
At least.
我必须回到飞船上
I have to get back to our ship.
下去太危险了 你需要休息
It's too dangerous down there. You need to rest.
维卡...
Vika...
别碰我
Don't touch me.
你的飞船重新进入地球是由地球表面的灯塔触发
Your ship's re-entry was triggered by a beacon from the surface.
你知道事情经过吗?
Do you know anything about that?
你的任务是什么?
What was your mission?
这是机密
It's classified.
我们对奥德赛号没有任何记录
Well, we have no record of an Odyssey...
在拿到飞船飞行记录之前
I can't tell you anything
我无可奉告
until I get the flight recorder from my ship.
茱莉亚 很多事在这60年之间都改变了
Julia, a lot has changed in 60 years.
在你深度睡眠期间
While you were in delta sleep,
地球遭到袭击
Earth was attacked.
外星掠夺者入侵
Call them scavs.
他们摧毁了我们的月球以及地球的一半土地
They destroyed our moon and with that, half the planet.
然后入侵地球
Then they invaded.
我们赢了战争
We won the war,
也毁了地球
but Earth was ruined.
所有人都在泰坦星上 就是土卫六
Everyone's on Titan now. It's a moon of Saturn.
还有些在空间站理 随时准备撤离
Or on the space station, getting ready to go.
我们在这里负责保障无人机的正常运行
We're here for security and drone maintenance.
我们是留守人员
We're the mop-up crew.
你是去了同伴
You've lost people.
失去了所有
Everything.
如果你想一个人静静 我们可以理解
If you want to be alone, we understand.
无人机屠杀了她的所有同伴
The drones killed her entire crew.
如果我不在那...
If I hadn't gotten there...
我想让她马上离开
I want her gone first thing.
维卡...
Vika...
你还有任务之前的记忆吗?
Do you have any memories before the mission?
安全消除记忆之前的记忆?
Before the security wipe?
我们的任务是遗忘
Our job is not to remember.
记得吗?
Remember?
你记得她吗?
Do you remember her?
杰克
Jack.
是掠夺者的信号让她降落的
That was a scav beacon that brought her down.
我们不知道她是人
We don't know who she is.
还是鬼
Or what she is.
先睡个安稳觉吧
Let's just get through the night.
好吗?
Okay?
你会开那个?
You fly that thing?
是的
Yes.
现在什么情况?
What happens now?
泰特马上就上线了
The Tet will be online soon.
维多利亚会汇报对你的营救行动
Victoria will report your rescue.
他们会派人来
They'll send someone down for you.
泰特派人来?
From the Tet?
是的
Yes.
我需要从我的飞船拿到飞行记录
I need to get the flight recorder from my ship.
掠夺者都在夜里行动
The scavs, they move at night.
他们现在可能已经占领那里了
They could be all over it by now.
我必须了解发生了什么
I need to know what happened.
你也必须了解发生了什么
You need to know what happened.
拜托
Please.
杰克?
Jack?
杰克 你在干什么?
Jack, what are you doing?
维卡 她是船长
Vika, she's a flight officer.
她想要看飞船上的飞行记录
She wants to see her ship and secure the flight recorder.
你也应该很想看
Now, you would want the same thing.
杰克 我...
Jack, I...
我无法护你周全
I can't protect you.
我理解
No, I understand.
这件事我自己负责
This one's on me.
我没办法救他们
I couldn't save them.
杰克 杰克!
Jack. Jack!
杰克 你听到我说话吗?
Jack, can you hear me?
好了 该走了
All right, it's time to go.
杰克
Jack.
我找到了
I found it.
杰克!
Jack!
49号指挥塔 在这个阳光明媚的早上 你们进展如何?
Tower 49, how are y'all this lovely morning?
如在天堂一般
Another day in paradise.
萨利...
Sally...
杰克凌晨去巡逻了
Jack took a pre-dawn patrol
在17区附近的峡谷
and went off-comm
失去了联络
near the canyons in 17.
我知道我们无人机不多
Now, I know we're low on drones,
不过我们需要一台去检查一下这个区
but, um, requesting one to sweep the area.
只是快速扫描一下
Just a quick scout.
收到 185号无人机即刻前往22区
Copy 49, tasking 185 to Grid 22.
"有什么比与厄运抗争而死 更死得其所"
"And how can a man die better than facing fearful odds."
"为了寻找先祖的遗迹"
"For the ashes of his fathers."
"以及其信仰的殿堂"
"And the temples of his Gods"
我一直在观察你 杰克
I've been watching you, Jack.
你很好奇
You're curious.
你想从那些书中找寻什么?
What are you looking for in those books?
它们让你想起了什么吗?
Do they bring back old memories?
你从我这得不到任何东西
You won't get anything from me.
我的记忆已经被抹去以保护...
My memory has been wiped to protect...
任务的安全 没错
The security of the mission. Yes.
你那宝贵的记忆
You can't have your precious memory
无法落入敌手了 是吗?
falling into the wrong hands, now, can you?
告诉我
Tell me.
你有没有如此接近过一个掠夺者?
Have you ever met a scav up close?
当然没有 你只修理无人机
Of course not. You just repair drones.
"禁止进入辐射区"
"Don't go into the radiation zone."
"不要质疑"
"Don't ask too many questions."
超出任务范围
Not part of the job description.
开灯
Lights.
我们不是外星人 杰克
We're not alien, Jack.
我们是人类
We're human.
当然 对于我们而言 作为人类是一个很大的麻烦
Of course, for us, being human is a problem.
老式隐形战斗机的技术 保护我们不被你们扫描到
Old stealth fighter tech. Shields us from your scanners.
声音干扰
Vocal scrambling.
能听到我说话吗 杰克?
Can you hear me, Jack?
迷惑你们的无人机
Keeps your drones confused.
当然 至少大部分时间可以
Well, most of the time.
无人机是用来...
The drones are programmed...
屠杀人类的 杰克
To kill humans, Jack.
你也看到他们屠杀冬眠仓里的人
You saw what they did to those sleep pods.
你为了救那个女人 差点被炸成碎片
You almost got yourself blown to bits protecting that woman.
你为什么这么做?
Why did you do that?
任何人都会这么做
Anyone would have.
"任何人"
"Anyone."
真有意思
Interesting.
我们这是在浪费时间
We're wasting our time.
无人机会来这儿找他的
The drone will track him here.
这是赛克斯中士
That's Sergeant Sykes.
他觉得我把你带到这里 是愚蠢的行为
He thinks I'm a fool for having brought you here.
希望你能证明他错了
I hope you prove him wrong.
长官 我在西部的峡谷里
Mission, I'm picking up a bio trail
发现了生物体痕迹
somewhere near the west canyons.
你能帮我确认基因序列吗?
Can you confirm the sequence?
稍等一下
Stand by.
基因确定是杰克的
DNA confirmed. It's Jack.
维卡 你没事吧?
Vika, are you okay?
你俩之间没什么问题吧?
Everything good between you two?
当然没有
Of course.
你们还是最佳组合吗?
You're still an effective team?
我们很好
We're great.
比以前都好
Never better.
我们当时在跑垒 结果那场比赛我们输了
We were running a ground game, and losing.
大家都在说"到底是怎么回事?"
So, we decided, "What the hell?"
"我们应该来个长传球的"
"We've got to throw the long ball."
我们花了几十年的时间破译全球定位系统的密码
It took us decades just to crack the GPS codes.
你们就是这样使奥德赛号降落的吧
That's how you brought down the Odyssey.
为什么?
Why?
奥德赛号上的小型反应堆是美国宇航局制造的
The Odyssey's compact reactor, courtesy of NASA.
现在已经很难找到了
Very hard to come by.
你喜欢昨晚的烟火表演吗?
Did you like the show last night?
那只是一个燃料电池
That was just one fuel cell.
想象一下 十个燃料电池
Imagine what 10 of them will do,
再加上一个武器级别的钚核心 会有多大的威力
with a core of weapons-grade plutonium.
我们有核武器 也有无人机来运送它
We have a nuke, and we have a drone to carry it.
但我们没法操作它 无人机不能识别我们
But we can't access it. It doesn't know who we are.
但是它能识别你 杰克
But it knows you, Jack.
你得帮我们重新给无人机编程
We need you to program the drone.
让它把我们的核武器运到泰特去
Have it carry our nuke up to the Tet.
结束这场战争
End this war.
泰特上有人类
There are people up there.
中士
Sergeant.
设置无人机返回泰特的程序
Program the drone to return to the Tet.
它必须降落在正中心的位置
It needs to go right to the center.
别做梦了
Screw you.
我们没有时间了
We haven't got time for this.
嘿 嘿！
Hey. Hey!
不
No.
- 我们走!  - 拉他起来
- Let's go!  - Get him up.
长官 185号刚刚从屏幕上消失了
Mission, 185 just went off-grid.
收到 指挥塔 我们也看见了
Copy, Tower, we're seeing the same thing.
我请求再派出两架无人机 可以吗?
Permission to task two additional drones?
一架无人机出现 其它的就会随之而来
If one drone is here, more will come.
他们不找到我就绝不罢休
And they won't stop until they find me.
它们会毁了这里的
They'll turn this place to dust.
但如果你放我们走 我就让它们停下
But if you let us go, I'll call them off.
这是你唯一的机会
It's your only chance.
我去过你们的
I've been to your
"辐射区域"
"radiation zones."
如果你想知道真相
If you're looking for the truth,
就去那里找吧
that's where you'll find it.
你在拿我们所有人的生命去冒险
You've risked all our lives. Everything.
你凭什么就认为他是不一样的?
What makes you think he's different?
因为她
She does.
油量不足
像在天堂一样
指挥中心 我在37区找到他了
Mission, I've found my tech over in 37.
可以取消搜索了
You can call off the search.
收到 塔台 真高兴杰克安全了
Copy that, Tower. Glad Jack's safe.
让其它无人机回去保护水电装置吧
Tasking the other drones back to rig support.
我们现在要去哪?
Where are we going now?
你是谁?
Who are you?
你为什么不告诉我?
What aren't you telling me?
杰克 我...
Jack, I...
你在奥德赛号上干什么?
What were you doing on the Odyssey?
你有什么任务?
What was your mission?
我的第一个任务是飞往泰坦星的探索飞行
It was a research flight to Titan. My first.
本来应该是这样的
That's what it was supposed to be.
出发前六个星期 深层空间探测器发现了一个外星物体
Six weeks to launch, deep space scanners picked up an alien object.
我们被派去调查
We were reassigned to investigate.
他们使我们进入了睡眠状态
They put us all in delta.
你和维多利亚一定是先被唤醒了
They must have woken you and Victoria first.
什么?
What?
杰克 那个外星物体
That object
就是泰特
was the Tet, Jack.
我们的任务就是调查泰特
The Tet was our mission.
不可能
That's impossible.
绝对不可能!
That's impossible!
你到底是谁?
Who are you?
我是你的妻子
I'm your wife.
我不知道发生了什么 但你绝不是你所认为的那个人
I don't know what happened, but you're not who you think you are.
杰克 我们曾经来过这里
Jack, we were here.
你让我和你见面 说要带我去这个世界最高的地方
You asked me to meet you, brought me up on top of the world.
我记得你那天有点紧张
I could tell you were nervous that day.
就是在这里 杰克
It was right here, Jack.
你说
You said,
"从这里看过去"
"Look through here,"
"就能看到我们的未来"
"And I'll show you the future."
然后我拿出了戒指
And I held up a ring.
你说...
And you said...
"我愿意"
"Yes."
你回来了
There you are.
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello.
来吧
Come on.
维卡 我回来了
Vika, I'm coming in.
在我回来之前别向总部汇报 行吗?
Do not report to Mission until I get back. Do you copy?
你听到了吗?
Do you copy?
维卡 开门
Vika, open the door.
离我远点
Stay away from me.
我不想听你解释
I don't want to hear it.
这里不安全 我们得离开这里 快
It's not safe here, and we need to leave, now.
你心里一直有她
It was always her.
不是吗?
Wasn't it?
维卡...
Vika...
她是我妻子
she's my wife.
指挥中心 这里是49号指挥塔
Mission, this is Tower 49.
请讲
Go ahead, 49.
别
No.
我和杰克之间出了一些问题
I'm having a problem with my technician.
别 你根本不知道你在干什么
No, you don't know what you're doing.
他在坠机点找到一个幸存者
He found a survivor at the crash site.
你得听我的
You've gotta listen to me.
他的工作能力受到了影响
She's impeding his abilities,
无法胜任现在的工作
and he is unfit for service.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
很遗憾听到这件事 维卡
I'm sorry to hear that, Vika.
你们还是最佳组合吗?
Are you still an effective team?
维卡...
Vika...
快点开门啊 维卡!
Open the goddamn door, Vika!
不
No.
我们现在不是最佳组合了
We are not an effective team.
维卡 拜托了 我们必须得走了
Vika, please. We have to go now.
我不会跟你去任何地方的 杰克
I'm not going anywhere with you, Jack.
我知道一个地方 那里很安全
There's a place I know. We'll be safe.
我要去泰坦星
I'm going to Titan.
根本就没有泰坦星
There is no Titan.
他们欺骗了我们
They lied to us.
离我远点
Just stay away from me.
维卡 求你了 有些事...
Vika, please, there are things...
有些事情你必须知道了
Things you need to know.
我不想知道!
I don't want to know!
杰克...
Jack...
嗨 杰克 真没想到我们还能见面
Hi, Jack. I don't believe we've had the pleasure.
你做了什么?
What have you done?
你不用太自责 无人机有时候并不可靠
You can't blame yourself for this. Drones are unreliable.
也会出问题
Sometimes things go wrong.
"出问题?"
"Go wrong"?
你杀了她
You killed her.
我知道 这是个悲剧 她很出色
I know, it's tragic. She was a wonderful person.
杰克 我们想带你回来
Jack, we want to bring you in.
我被授权通知你
I've been authorized to tell you
我们要分配给你新的任务
we're going to assign you a new mission.
和幸存者一起
You and the survivor.
这里的人对她很感兴趣 把她带来
There's a lot of interest up here. Bring her up.
我们可以把一切都调查清楚
We can debrief, then anything's possible.
是时候回家了 杰克
It's time to come home, Jack.
杰克?
Jack?
杰克
Jack
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
坐稳了
Hang on.
闪电
Lightning.
这就是我的计划
That's the plan.
我们需要掩护
We need cover.
那里
There.
- 你还好吗?  - 不好
- Are you okay?  - No.
别担心 我们不会进去的
Don't worry, we're staying out of there.
我们要死了吗?
Are we gonna die?
不!
No!
有可能
Maybe.
杰克!
Jack!
该死
Son of a bitch.
在这等我
Wait here.
那是谁?
Who is it?
嘿!
Hey!
等一下!
Wait!
嘿!
Hey!
放下武器!
Drop your weapon!
没关系的
It's okay.
不许动!
Don't move!
我们得关了那个无人机
We have to shut that drone down.
别动!
Stop moving!
杰克!
Jack!
没事了
It's okay.
茱莉亚
Julia.
茱莉亚!
Julia!
别
Don't.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
坚持住
Hold on.
要坚持住
Just hold on.
杰克・哈珀 52号技术员
Jack Harper, Tech-52.
嘿
Hey.
原来你在这
There you are.
发生了什么? 你还好吗?
What happened? Are you okay?
那个不明飞行器越过边界 然后就联络不上你了
That bogey came across the border and then I lost you.
那是假警报
False alarm.
我得回去了
I should get back out there.
你好不容易才回家 连吻我都不肯?
You come all the way home, and I don't get a kiss?
你在想什么?
What's going on up there?
我在想...
I was thinking...
你为什么不和我一起下去?
why don't you come down with me?
一起去地上?
To the surface?
我们现在就可以出发了
We could go right now.
现在?
Now?
是
Yeah.
没开玩笑吧?
Are you serious?
下面发生的一切会让你大吃一惊
You won't believe what's down there.
杰克
Jack.
你知道规定的
You know the regulations.
是
Yes.
我们别这样了 好吗? 我不想再讨论这些了
Can we not do this again? I'm done talking about it.
好
Okay.
接下来会有点疼
This is gonna hurt.
糟透了 是吧 鲍伯?
Hell of a day, huh, Bob?
你一直很喜欢这首歌
You always loved this song.
我不是他
I'm not him.
我知道我不是
I know I'm not.
但我爱过你...
But I've loved you...
自我有记忆以来
for as long as I can remember.
我不知道还该怎么说
I don't know how else to say it.
你记得你曾经和我说过的吗?
You know what you said to me once?
你说 当一切结束以后 你会为我在湖边建一座房子
You said when it was all over, you would build me a house on a lake.
我们会一起变老 变胖
We would grow old and fat together.
我们也会吵架
And we would fight.
可能是因为喝多了
Maybe drink too much.
好浪漫
Real romantic.
然后我们一起死去
And then we would die
葬在湖边的草地
and be buried in a meadow by the lake.
世界会忘了我们
And the world would forget about us.
但我们能一直和对方在一起
But we would always have each other.
我记得
I remember.
这些记忆是你的 杰克
Those memories are yours, Jack.
是我们的
They're ours.
它们是你
They are you.
早上好
Good morning.
我曾经想下半生都住在这里
I wanted to spend the rest of my life here.
现在你也可以的
You still can.
我得走了
I have to go.
那些人需要我的帮助
Those people need my help.
一切结束的时候我们会回来的
We'll come back when it's over.
答应我
Promise me.
一切结束的时候我们会回来的
We'll come back when it's over.
你曾经让我很担心
You had me worried for a second.
我以为你不会回来了
I thought you weren't coming back.
看来我证明他是错的
Well, I had to prove him wrong.
你看起来糟透了
You look like shit.
你应该去看看另一个我
You should see the other guy.
如果我之前告诉你 你会在那里发现什么
If I had told you what you'd find out there,
你会觉得我疯了
you would have thought I was crazy.
我现在也这么觉得
I still do.
马尔科姆・比奇
Malcolm Beech.
茱莉亚・哈珀
Julia Harper.
跟我来
Come on.
指挥中心 在西峡谷附近
Mission, I'm picking up a bio-trail
发现生物痕迹
somewhere near the West Canyons.
能否确认序列?
Can you confirm the sequence?
准备确认
Stand by.
基因确认 是杰克
DNA confirmed, it's Jack.
报告 185号失去了信号
Mission, 185 just went off-grid.
收到 我也发现了
Copy, Tower. We're seeing the same thing.
当罪恶的泰特来的时候 我服役还不到一年
I'd been in the army less than a year when that unholy Tet arrived.
我看到月球被毁灭
I saw the moon get taken out.
就在夜空里
Right up there in the night sky.
我简直不敢相信
I couldn't believe it.
后来大自然发怒了
After that, nature took over.
在芝加哥周围有基岩
There's bedrock around Chicago,
因此我们才能躲过海啸和地震
so we were spared the worst of the waves and the quakes.
很多人饿死了
Most people just starved.
然后从泰特派来许多运输船
Then the Tet sent troop ships down.
门开了
The doors opened,
你走了出来
and out you came.
宇航员杰克・哈珀
Astronaut Jack Harper.
数千个你
Thousands of you.
记忆清除
Memory wiped.
程序设定为杀人
Programmed to kill.
他们让我们中最优秀的一员
They had taken one of our best
来对付我们
and turned him against us.
没有灵魂
No soul.
没有人性
No humanity.
泰特
The Tet.
多聪明的机器
What a brilliant machine.
吃光了一个又一个星球的能量
Feeding off one planet after another for energy.
第二阶段是无人机
Phase Two was drones.
技术员
Repairmen.
50年来 我们一直看着那些水电装置吸干我们的地球
50 years of watching those hydro rigs suck our planet dry.
然后有一天
Then one day,
我看见你在那里着陆
I saw you set down.
需要修理另一个无人机
Another drone to fix.
但那天 你在碎石堆里看到了一本书
But in the rubble that day was a book.
你捡起那本书
You picked it up.
反复研究
You studied it.
我觉得我找到了一种方法
And I thought I saw a way.
当你挡住那架无人机并救了她的时候
When you stepped in front of that drone and saved her,
我就知道了
I knew.
你就在你身体里的某个地方
You were in there somewhere.
我只需要找到一种方法来把你带回来
I just had to find a way to bring you back.
小心 小心
Watch it, watch it.
盯着它 小心
Eyes on it. Steady.
给它一点空间
Give it some space.
放松 你们让它紧张了
Come on, you're making it nervous.
那是一种罪恶的武器
That is one pissed-off weapon.
不 这就是个机器
No, it's just a machine.
我是武器
I'm the weapon.
当这玩意爆炸的时候
I would love to be there to see
我多想去看看那家伙的表情
that thing's face when this goes off.
那可是一条不归路
That would be a one-way trip.
是啊 但很值得
Yeah, but it would be worth it.
欢迎回来 指挥官
Welcome back, Commander.
开门!
Open the doors!
该死!
Shit!
快散开!
Spread out!
低头 把头低下!
Head down, keep your head down!
杰克!
Jack!
跟着我!
Follow me!
来吧 你个小杂种!
Come on, you son of a bitch!
嘿!
Hey!
杰克
Jack.
我没事
I'm okay.
那架无人机
The drone.
把那架无人机运出去
Send the drone.
毁了
It's gone.
我以为我们成功了
I thought we had it.
我真的这么想
I really did.
我自己带炸弹过去
I can take the bomb myself.
啊...
Ah...
你明知炸弹会把你像苍蝇一样轰个稀烂吧
You know it will swat you like a fly.
我去就不会这样了
Not if I go.
不行
No.
她要你把我带去
She asked you to bring me up.
照她说的做吧
So bring me up.
我们一起去
We'll go together.
这幅画让我有种家的感觉
It reminds me of home.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
杰克
Jack.
记得梦到我们
Dream of us.
杰克?
Jack?
奥德赛号飞行记录回放
Flight recorder playback for the Odyssey mission.
2017年5月3日
3 May, 2017.
好了 鲍伯
Okay, Bob.
准备好冲上云霄了吗?
Ready for space?
早上好 奥德赛号 来自指挥中心的朋友的问候
Good morning, Odyssey, from your friends here at Mission Control.
早上好 指挥中心 我是指挥官杰克・哈珀
Good morning, Mission. This is Commander Jack Harper.
多谢你贴心的早晨叫醒服务
Thank you for that fantastic wake-up call.
会合前检查完成
Pre-rendezvous checks complete.
电子导航系统一切正常
Electrical guidance and nav systems, all good.
驶近目标后方 相距250节...
Range behind object, 250 clicks...
水平向下12节 驶近速度200千米每小时
12 below V-bar, closure rate 200 kilometers per hour.
收到 杰克 很高兴见到你
Copy that. It's good to see you, Jack.
39天的休眠之后 你似乎已经准备好出发了
After 39 days of sleep, sounds like you're ready to go.
我准备好出发了
I'm ready to go.
下一次开动会带你到另一个层次
Your next burn will bring you up level
同步速度在50千米范围内 你在那个地方悬停
and co-speed at 50 kilometer range, where you'll hold.
明白 我们停在距目标50节的地方
Copy. We'll hold 50 clicks from object
等候传感器扫描及评估
for sensor scan and evaluation.
目标正常
Targets look good.
启动倒计时 3 2 1...
Initiating burn in 3,2,1...
启动
Ignition.
启动很稳定
We see a good burn.
收到目标的输出数据了吗?
Are you reading any output from the object?
没有
Negative.
温度为零 没有反应
Zero heat. No EMR.
没有生命迹象
There's no sign of life.
其他宇航员状况如何?
How is the rest of the crew doing?
副驾驶维多利亚・奥森马上就会醒过来
Co-pilot Victoria Olsen should be up here shortly.
其他宇航员仍处于深度睡眠状态
The rest of the crew remains in delta sleep.
收到
Copy that.
你昨晚可是错过了一场重要比赛哟
You missed a hell of a game last night.
我跟你们说什么来着? 别剧透
What did I tell you guys? No spoilers about last night's game.
我还想着回来再看比赛呢
I'm looking forward to watching it when I get back.
你不会又开始说足球了吧?
You're not talking about football already, are you?
早上好 维卡
Good morning, Vika.
早上好 萨利
Good morning, Sally.
阳光明媚的早晨 你们紧张如何?
How are you doing this lovely morning?
如天堂一般
Another day in paradise.
嘿
Hey.
留作纪念
One for history.
号
Yeah.
49号技术员 你正在靠近中
Tech-49, I have you on approach.
你好啊 萨利
Hello, Sally.
早上很忙吧?
It's a busy morning, huh?
杰克 我发现有第二个乘客
I'm picking up a second passenger, Jack.
她叫茱莉亚・罗萨科娃
It's Julia Rusakova,
是坠毁飞船的幸存者
the female survivor from the crashed module.
说出你的目的
State your intention.
按照要求 送返幸存者
Deliver the survivor, as requested.
我们是
We are
更好的组合
a more effective team.
准备进入
Proceed to entry.
指挥中心 出问题了
Mission, we have a situation.
最后一次启动准确无误 乃是为了静止观察目标
The last burn was spot-on to give us a SO-click hold from object,
但雷达范围仍在不断缩小
but radar range still decreasing.
我们正在向目标加速前进
We're accelerating toward the object.
我们需要全力启动停电系统 抛离目标
We're going to need full OMS burn to pull away.
- 马上启动  - 输入目标位置
- Initiate now.  - Entering target.
- 平衡环已启动  - 目标正常
- Gimbals set.  - Target's good.
- 启动前置引擎  - 引擎已启动
- Arm forward engines.  - Engines on.
准备好了吗 出发
Ready? Let's go.
指挥中心 我们已全力启动停电系统 正在后退
Mission, we're in full OMS burn, trying to back out.
好大的动静
There's a lot of vibration.
我们逃不过这一劫了
We're not getting away from this thing.
奥德赛号 遥测数据显示结构受压过度
Odyssey, telemetry shows structural overstress.
关掉系统 收到明白吗?
Knock off the burn. Do you copy?
关掉系统
Cutting off burn.
指挥中心
Mission.
指挥中心? 指挥中心?
Mission? Mission?
萨利?
Sally?
朝向目标继续加速
Increased acceleration toward the object.
预计两分钟内撞击
Estimated contact within two minutes.
我要弹射睡眠舱
I'm going to eject the sleep module.
它们会按预定重新进入地球轨道
It's programmed for reinsertion into Earth orbit.
若我空出手来 就驾驶指挥舱
I'll fly the Command module out if I break free.
- 我要你马上回睡眠舱去  - 不行
- I want you back there now.  - Absolutely not.
这是命令!
That's an order!
杰克 不行 我们是一个团队
Jack, no, we're a team.
该走了 杰克! 还有30秒!
We've got to go, Jack! 30 seconds!
记得梦到我们
Dream of us.
杰克?
Jack?
49号技术员 以航行速度进入指挥中心
Tech-49, enter at headway speed.
以航行速度进入指挥中心
Entering at headway.
系好安全带 鲍伯
You buck up, Bob.
别给我摇头了
Don't go all shaky on me.
杰克 我注意到
Jack, I can't help notice
你的呼吸和心跳速度都提高了
your respiration and heart rate have increased.
萨利 终于见到了你 我很兴奋
I'm just excited to finally meet you, Sally.
最近反抗都模式化了
There's been a pattern of insubordinate behavior recently.
是啊
Yeah.
我也挺担心的
I feel bad about that.
杰克 语音分析表明你在对我撒谎
Voice analysis indicates you are lying to me, Jack.
说出你到这里的真实目的
Tell me why you are here.
给你5秒钟时间回答
You have five seconds.
我想让茱莉亚活下去
I want Julia to live.
我想让人类活下去
I want our species to survive.
这是唯一的办法
This is the only way.
准备着陆 大气已备妥
Proceed to landing. Atmosphere provided.
杰克 欢迎回来
Welcome home, Jack.
来吧
Come on.
杰克 你做得对
Jack, you're doing the right thing.
我不知道你是什么东西 来自何方
I don't know what you are, or where you're from,
不过我告诉你些我读到的东西
but I'd like to tell you about something I read.
是个罗马故事
A story from Rome,
一个被你摧毁的城市
a city you destroyed.
很经典的故事
It's a classic.
有个叫贺拉斯的家伙
There was a guy, Horatius,
面对整支军队 独自扛起一座桥
held the bridge alone against a whole army.
贺拉斯说道
And what Horatius said was,
"有什么比与厄运抗争而死..."
"How can a man die better..."
杰克 你不用死 她也不用死
You don't have to die, Jack. She doesn't have to die.
萨利 人总有一死
Everybody dies, Sally.
关键是 要死得有尊严
The thing is, to die well.
杰克 这不是你说的幸存者
Jack, that's not the survivor you promised me.
没错 这不是
No, it's not.
贺拉斯说道
What Horatius said was,
"有什么比与厄运抗争而死"
"How can a man die better."
"更死得其所"
"Than facing fearful odds".
无人机! 快进去! 进去!
Drones! Get inside! Get inside!
"为了寻找先祖的遗迹"
"For the ashes of his fathers."
"以及其信仰的殿堂"
"And the temples of his Gods".
杰克 我一手造就了你
I created you, Jack.
我就是你的神
I am your God.
去死吧 萨利
Fuck you, Sally.
这是战争后的地球
Earth, after the war.
上次见到你 还是三年前的事了
Three years have passed since I saw your face.
我疑惑 夜间梦境里是否追寻过你
I wonder if I come to you at night, in dreams.
而在白天 则从记忆中寻找你的身影
In the day, as memories.
你我的时间是否一致?
Do I haunt your hours the way you haunted mine?
我疑惑 当你凝视她时
And I wonder if you see me
是否看到我的影子
when you look at her.
妈妈 快看
Mommy, look.
若我们有灵魂 也是由共同的爱铸就
If we have souls, they are made of the love we share.
经时间打磨
Undimmed by time.
被死亡拆散
Unbound by death.
三年来 我搜寻着他建的那所房子
For three years, I searched for the house he built.
我知道 它一定就在那里
I knew it had to be out there.
因为我了解他
Because I know him.
打过他
Lam him.
那是谁?
Who's that?
我是杰克・哈珀
I am Jack Harper.
我回家了
And I am home.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤
翻译: 潇妹纸 袋鼠 有个饭团 凤梨酥 汐颜viola
校对: 影子